<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archived Projects | Xiangyu Zhao</title>
    <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Archived Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Xiangyu Zhao</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://victorzxy.github.io/media/icon_hu445124fc86f9a5e0ef5204885c05fa2c_2309_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Archived Projects</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Adversarial Examples for Deep Residual Networks</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/fgsm-attack-resnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/fgsm-attack-resnets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I investigated the one-shot and iterative fast gradient sign method (FGSM) attack, both untargeted and targeted, to generate adversarial examples for ResNet-50, and experimented the transferability of each FGSM to other neural networks, namely ResNet-18 and VGG-19, as well as other image inputs. The following conclusions can be reached after the above experiments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeted FGSM is more effective than FGSM;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In white-box attacks, both the untargeted and targeted one-shot FGSMs are less effective than the iterative methods (both untargeted and targeted);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it comes to transferability to other neural networks or inputs, the one-shot FGSMs turn out to be much more effective than the iterative FGSMs, as the iterative FGSMs suffer from overfitting and hence completely unable to transfer to other neural networks or inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since transferability is a foundation to black-box attacks, it is likely that the one-shot FGSMs can also be more effective than the iterative FGSMs in black-box attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Clickstream Data for Online Shopping</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/datasci-pnp-final-practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/datasci-pnp-final-practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I analysed a clickstream dataset of an online shopping website for clothing between April and August 2008, and built a machine learning pipeline to predict the costumer’s potential willingness to pay a premium price. I explored, trained and compared various machine learning models for this task, ranging from traditional models to deep neural networks, and identified the most important features for predicting the target value. The best-performing model the I trained for this project has achieved a test accuracy of 93.37%. I also performed visualisation and dimensionality reduction, using PCA and t-SNE, to reveal properties of the dataset and my models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading Assistant</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/trading-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/trading-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an web service written in Python and JavaScript, developed for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imc.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IMC Trading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all trading happens on the exchanges—sometimes counterparties trade directly through human-to-human communication. In such cases, humans typically use their most natural interface: voice. The Trading Assistant holds market data and responds to queries on demand in a human-like manner, by automating the trader side of the trading communication using modern technologies, including speech recognition, natural language processing, and speech synthesis. The speech recognition and speech synthesis module of the Trading Assistant was built based on the Google Cloud Speech-to-Text and Text-to-Speech APIs. The Trading Assistant also adopts a Naïve Bayes approach for NLP, using word2vec for word embeddings and Siamese BERT for sentence embeddings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for building the speech recognition and speech synthesis modules, and efficiently built the libraries with high accuracies, and provided clean interfaces that were used conveniently by my NLP and back-end teammates, improving the system&amp;rsquo;s overall performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iSport</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/isport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/isport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Android application, written in Java, for the athletes in Cambridge. It gives a daily weather forecast information on the most relevant weather, based on the user&amp;rsquo;s selection of sports. I was responsible for layout design and interaction functionalities, and built an aesthetic, easy-to-use and efficient user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Classroom Teaching Tool for Graph Theory</title>
      <link>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/graph-teaching-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victorzxy.github.io/archive/graph-teaching-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Graph theory is an important part in A-Level mathematics and computer science subjects. A good majority of students who are studying mathematics, further mathematics or computer science need a more hands-on approach to this very abstract subject which lies at the heart of computer science, and a detailed and easy-understandable teaching tool is essential to their understandings about graph theory. Unfortunately, however, such a teaching tool is quite rare to find in the majority of academic supportive websites. In this project, I built a Windows desktop application in C#, that provides a classroom teaching tool for graph theory, particularly in the following algorithms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prim&amp;rsquo;s and Kruskal&amp;rsquo;s minimum spanning trees algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s single-source shortest paths algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teaching tool enables a user to freely create a graph by filling in an adjacency matrix/list, and also provides a Sketch Board which allows a user to directly draw the graph on a canvas. It then applies the graph algorithms on the created graph, with step-by-step demonstrations. It also embeds a Question Bank for teachers to set, edit and store questions and students to answer them, together with an automatic marking system, and can keep track of the learning progress of each student.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
